<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</title>
    <link>/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on UVA Biocomplexity Institute</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic Analyses of White &amp; Black Soldiers</title>
      <link>/findings/02-s32-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/02-s32-eda/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 32 was given out to soldiers in 1943, approximately 5 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 7442 black soldiers and 4793 white soldiers and asked for basic demographic information, career aspirations, and more but of interests to us, Survey 32 asked the soldiers for their opinions on integration of military outfits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic Analyses of Black Soldiers</title>
      <link>/findings/03-s144-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/03-s144-eda/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Who Are the Soldiers? Survey 144 was given out to soldiers in 1944, approximately 4 years before the military was integrated. The survey was passed out to 4,678 black soldiers and focused on post-war plans and aspirations of the soldiers. We were particularly interested in how the soldiers thought their lives would be better after the war.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis of Gender Relations Survey</title>
      <link>/findings/04-s195-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/findings/04-s195-eda/</guid>
      <description>/* this chunnk of code centers all of the headings */ h1, h2, h3 { text-align: center; }  Introduction In addition to race relations in the Army, we are also focused on perspectives on women and gender within the military. The questions and responses are mostly geared towards WACs, which are Women&#39;s Army Corps members. In addition to survey 32, which captures textual data on gender in teh Army, a survey was given out in January of 1945 to capture perspectives of male soldiers on their WAC counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>